<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>RNA-seq data analysis - Tag - YY&#39;s homepage</title>
        <link>https://youeny.github.io/tags/rna-seq-data-analysis/</link>
        <description>RNA-seq data analysis - Tag - YY&#39;s homepage</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://youeny.github.io/tags/rna-seq-data-analysis/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Drawing Volcano plot (1)</title>
    <link>https://youeny.github.io/2022-05-17-drawing-volcano-plot/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://youeny.github.io/2022-05-17-drawing-volcano-plot/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Here is the final result of this article:
This volcano plot contains:
 up-regulated/not-significant/down-regulated genes which are highlighted in red and blue lines show log2FoldChange = -1/1, adjusted p value = 0.05 Top 10 genes names beside their points which is greatly changed  Let&rsquo;s start!]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>What is the RNA-seq analysis?</title>
    <link>https://youeny.github.io/2022-05-16-what-is-the-rna-seqribo-seq-analysis/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://youeny.github.io/2022-05-16-what-is-the-rna-seqribo-seq-analysis/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Overall description of RNA-Seq The transcriptome has a high degree of complexity including multiple types of coding and non-coding RNA species, like mRNA, pre-mRNA, microRNA, and long ncRNA. To understand how the expression of a gene affects translation to proteins, messenger RNA (mRNA) molecules were the most frequently studied RNA species. Besides coding RNA, noncoding RNA molecules also play significant roles in cellular functions: Ribosomal RNAs and transfer RNAs are involved in mRNA translation.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>The basic principle of DESeq2</title>
    <link>https://youeny.github.io/the-basic-principle-of-deseq2/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://youeny.github.io/the-basic-principle-of-deseq2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[How DESeq2 calculate DEGs? DESeq2 tool was published in 2014 and it has been cited more than 30,000 times. (reference)
 DESeq2 is a method for differential analysis of count data, using shrinkage estimation for dispersions and fold changes to improve the stability and interpretability of estimates.
 Library normalization by DEGs (median of ratios method) RPKM, FPKM, TPM&hellip;&hellip; Those are methods for adjusting for the difference in overall read counts among libraries.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RNA-seq protocol(2) Trim the read files using trim_galore</title>
    <link>https://youeny.github.io/trim-the-read-files-using-trim_galore/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://youeny.github.io/trim-the-read-files-using-trim_galore/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Summary  In this section, we are going to install trimgalore and trim the merged read files to improve the qualities of read files.   1. Why do we need to trim?  Quality trimming decreases the overall number of reads, but increases to the total and proportion of uniquely mapped reads. Thus, you get more useful data for downstream analyses. Too aggressive quality trimming can negatively impact downstream analysis.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RNA-seq protocol(3) Mapping (STAR&#43;Qualimap&#43;featureCounts)</title>
    <link>https://youeny.github.io/mapping-star-qualimap-featurecounts/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://youeny.github.io/mapping-star-qualimap-featurecounts/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Summary  In this section, we are going to map the read files to genome index using STAR, perform QC with Qualimap, and obtain count data using featureCounts.   1. installation of STAR  Pl ease refer to this official manual
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10  # Get latest STAR source from releases wget https://github.com/alexdobin/STAR/archive/2.7.9a.tar.gz tar -xzf 2.7.9a.tar.gz cd STAR-2.7.9a # Compile under Linux cd /STAR-2.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RNA-seq protocol(1) Preparation of clean read data for RNA-seq data analysis</title>
    <link>https://youeny.github.io/preparation-of-clean-reads-data-for-rna-seq/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://youeny.github.io/preparation-of-clean-reads-data-for-rna-seq/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Summary  In this section, we are going to concatenate 4 read files from the same sample into 1 file and perform Fastqc, multiqc, and Trim_galore to check the quality of each read data.   1     1. Concatenation of raw read files First of all, the operating system (OS) I used is Linux Ubuntu 20.04.4. And what I have in my hand are 64 raw read fastq.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
